<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>HN Summaries</title><link>http://andrewpoirier.github.io/hn_summarizer</link><description>The top HN articles everyday - summarized</description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:33:13 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>1. Texture-Less Text Rendering</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093037</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;198 points points by PaulHoule on 2024-11-09T07:27:56 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website focuses on providing insights and resources related to the concept of "reflective practice" in various contexts, emphasizing its importance for personal and professional development. It likely offers tools, examples, and methodologies to help individuals effectively engage in reflective practices to enhance their learning and growth. The goal is to promote self-awareness and continuous improvement through reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If anyone wants to try this, work through the artithmetic, it’s incredibly easy (and a fun Saturday morning exercise if you’re into this kind of thing) to code up on ShaderToy. From scratch is fun, but if you need a hint to get started I just made one https://www.shadertoy.com/view/Mc3cW2 and there are a bunch of super clever text hacks other people have done like this Matrix in less than 300 characters https://www.shadertoy.com/view/llXSzj or green CRT display effect https://www.shadertoy.com/view/XtfSD8. Loads of other examples abound if you look around.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is delightfully clever and hacky (so basically like every 3d rendering technique ever) but the end result isn't exactly beautiful unless you're trying to recreate an old school electronic billboard. You could improve it by adding more bits, but long before it starts to look good you'd be searching for an easier way to handle setting all the bits... And there's almost certainly no more efficient solution than using black and white pixels in a drawing program then saving the results in a texture. So, full circle.If anyone is interested in the a more common way that modern 3d rendering engines draw text, look up SDF text (and related techniques like MSDF etc.). This uses a traditional texture atlas in a preprossing step to create an atlas of signed distance fields.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There's also the option of rendering text as meshes.TextMeshPro goes one step further and uses signed distance fields to handle arbitrary scale.https://docs.unity3d.com/Packages/com.unity.textmeshpro@4.0/...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:25:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093037</guid></item><item><title>2. Can humans say the largest prime number before we find the next one?</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42031642</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;303 points points by robinhouston on 2024-11-03T07:28:00 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I got strong "The Nine Billion Names of God" vibes from this!Just as the last video is uploaded, without any fuss, the stars start going out...https://urbigenous.net/library/nine_billion_names_of_god.htm...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;So, each human gets 419 digits from a pool of ~41M digits, or a target of ~100k videos uploaded.This is the weirdest DDoS attack on YouTube I've seen.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The key is to say it in a base-M136279841 number system.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:25:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42031642</guid></item><item><title>3. Delta: A syntax-highlighting pager for Git, diff, grep, and blame output</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091365</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;590 points points by nateb2022 on 2024-11-08T23:46:46 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delta is a syntax-highlighting pager for git and diff output that enhances the readability of diffs in the terminal. It formats git diff output with color-coded differences, making it easier for users to review changes in code visually. Delta is designed to be customizable, allowing users to adjust colors, styles, and behavior to suit their needs. It also supports various features, such as paging, the ability to show word differences, and integration with tools like GitHub and GitLab. The project is open-source and actively maintained on GitHub, where users can find installation instructions and contribute to its development.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Delta has been one of those set and forget things, it's been a while since I've seen 'bare' git grep/diff/blame output, I also use it all the time for normal diffs (outside of git repos), but TIL that it also works with ripgrep [0]As someone else already mentioned there is also bat[1], which was also set and forget, I aliased cat to bat and have a seperate alias vcat for 'vanilla cat' /usr/bin/cat[0] https://dandavison.github.io/delta/grep.html[1] https://github.com/sharkdp/bat&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There was a good point made, that has stuck with me over the years. that our syntax highlighters are highlighting the wrong thing.They should not be coloring the grammar, we are good at picking out grammar, they should be highlighting the symbols. each different variable and function name should be getting it's own color. that is, the goal is to make it quicker to distinguish different symbols, not that they are a symbol.But this is much harder than stylizing the grammar so all our tooling sticks with the easy thing rather that the useful thing. Now, I am being a bit mean on grammar styling. It does help quite a bit but I would like to see a symbol matching engine in action to see if that really works.Unfortunately I don't remember where I read the original post and am unable to attribute it correctly.update: while trying to look it up I found this https://www.wilfred.me.uk/blog/2014/09/27/the-definitive-gui...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Speaking of diffs, one thing that annoys me about Git's diff output is that is prints file paths like Unix diff traditionally does, starting with the two file names:    --- a/some/path/to/file.c
    +++ b/some/path/to/file.c

I often cmd-click in iTerm to open a file in an editor, but this doesn't work here because of the a/ and b/ prefixes. Any way to make Git format the file name better? I don't even need two lines here.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:25:23 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091365</guid></item><item><title>4. Scientist treated her own cancer with viruses she grew in the lab</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42094573</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;568 points points by dataminer on 2024-11-09T14:23:30 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the recent developments in research related to gene editing technologies, particularly CRISPR, and their potential applications in treating genetic disorders. It highlights breakthroughs made by scientists in refining these tools to enhance precision and reduce off-target effects in gene modification. The piece also examines ethical considerations and regulatory challenges associated with the use of CRISPR in humans, stressing the need for responsible advancements in the field amidst growing interest from both the scientific community and the public.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Absolutely metal and the person I would aspire to be.I can't imagine a higher motivation to study and find a cure than to save yourself, with the possible exception of saving a loved one.As other have mentioned, finding a cure for a specific case is easier and has less regulations than finding a general cure.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The one silver lining of having such a terrible diagnosis should be that you are immediately unbound from normal FDA requirements and are able and try anything in the pipeline that might work.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I can see possible ethical objections, for example if there was a risk that one of these self-ministered viruses was contagious (no idea) that would create scope for harming people.Of if it was a form of embezzlement or something, like there was funding for X and it got used for “treat my own cancer” that would be bad.But TFA seems to say that the ethical problem is “did experiment risky to the patient on myself”, which just seems strictly more ethically clear than “do experiment risky to the patient on other people”, which is a norm, but a regrettable necessity.Did I misread it?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:25:33 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42094573</guid></item><item><title>5. Mergiraf: a syntax-aware merge driver for Git</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093756</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;377 points points by p4bl0 on 2024-11-09T11:06:10 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mergiraf.org is dedicated to promoting sustainable development and fostering partnerships between various stakeholders, including governments, NGOs, and the private sector. The organization focuses on environmental protection, social equity, and economic growth by implementing programs that address climate change, biodiversity loss, and social challenges. Mergiraf emphasizes collaboration and knowledge sharing to create impactful solutions that benefit communities and the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Looking at the architecture, they will probably run into some issues. We are doing something similar with SemanticDiff [1] and also started out using tree-sitter grammars for parsing and GumTree for matching. Both choices turned out to be problematic.Tree sitter grammars are primarily written to support syntax highlighting and often use a best effort approach to parsing. This is perfectly fine for syntax highlighting, since the worst that can happen is that a few characters are highlighted incorrectly. However, when diffing or modifying code you really want the code to be parsed according to the upstream grammar, not something that mostly resembles it. We are currently in the process of moving away from tree-sitter and instead using the parsers provided by the languages themselves where possible.GumTree is good at returning a result quickly, but there are quite a few cases where it always returned bad matches for us, no matter how many follow-up papers with improvements we tried to implement. In the end we switched over to a dijkstra based approach that tries to minimize the cost of the mapping, which is more computationally expensive but gives much better results. Difftastic uses a similar approach as well.[1]: https://semanticdiff.com/&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The tool has an excellent architecture section [0] that goes into how it works under the hood.  It stands out to me that a complex tool has an overview to this depth that allows you to grasp conceptually how it works.0 - https://mergiraf.org/architecture.html&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Going through the sorts of conflicts it solves, and limitations in that, I find it claiming that in some insertions, order doesn’t matter &lt;https://mergiraf.org/conflicts.html#neighbouring-insertions-...&gt;.I really don’t like that. At the language level, order may not matter, but quite frequently in such cases the order does matter, insofar as almost every human would put the two things in a particular order; or where there is a particular convention active. If you automatically merge the two sides in a different order from that, doing it automatically has become harmful.My clearest example: take Base `struct Foo; struct Bar;`, then between these two items, Left inserts `impl Foo { }`, Right inserts `struct Baz;`. To the computer, the difference doesn’t matter, but merging it as `struct Foo; struct Baz; impl Foo { } struct Bar;` is obviously bad to a human. This is the problem: it’s handling language syntax semantics, but can’t be aware of logical semantics. (Hope you can grasp what I’m trying to convey, not sure of the best words.) Left was not inserting something between Foo and Bar, it was attaching something to the end of Foo. Whereas Right was probably inserting something between Foo and Bar—but maybe even it was inserting something before Bar. You perceive that these are all different things, logically.Another example where this will quickly go wrong: in CSS rulesets, some will sort the declarations by property name lexicographically, some by property name length (seriously, it’s frequently so pretty), some will group by different types of property… you can’t know.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:25:43 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093756</guid></item><item><title>6. Show HN: HTML-to-Markdown – convert entire websites to Markdown with Golang/CLI</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093511</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;310 points points by JohannesKauf on 2024-11-09T09:48:08 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GitHub repository for "html-to-markdown" provides a tool for converting HTML documents into Markdown format. It is designed to simplify the process of extracting content from HTML while preserving the structure and readability. The project includes detailed documentation, installation instructions, and examples demonstrating its usage. It employs a customizable approach, allowing users to tailor the conversion process to meet their specific needs. The repository also encourages contributions from the community to improve functionality and support additional use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you need this sort of thing in any other language, there's a free, no-auth, no-api-key-required, no-strings-attached API that can do this at https://jina.ai/reader/You just fetch a URL like `https://r.jina.ai/https://www.asimov.press/p/mitochondria`, and get a markdown document for the "inner" URL.I've actually used this and it's not perfect, there are websites (mostly those behind Cloudflare and other such proxies) that it can't handle, but it does 90% of the job, and is an one-liner in most languages with a decent HTTP requests library.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pandochttp://www.cantoni.org/2019/01/27/converting-html-markdown-u...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nice! And glad to see it's MIT licensed.I wonder if it is feasible to use this as a replacement for p2k, instapaper etc for the purpose of reading on Kindle. One annoyance with these services is that the rendering is way off -- h elements not showing up as headers, elements missing randomly, source code incorrectly rendered in 10 different ways. Some are better than others, but generally they are disappointing. (Yet they expect you to pay a subscription fee.) If this is an actively maintained project that welcomes contribution, I could test it out with various articles and report/fix issues. Although I wonder how much work there will be for handling edge cases of all the websites out there.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:25:53 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093511</guid></item><item><title>7. Obtainium: Get Android App Updates Directly from the Source</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42026251</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;206 points points by janandonly on 2024-11-02T13:24:05 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obtainium is a platform designed to help users easily acquire and manage NFTs and cryptocurrencies. It offers a user-friendly interface that simplifies the process of minting, buying, and trading digital assets while providing tools for tracking and managing portfolios. The site emphasizes security and provides resources for both beginners and experienced users to navigate the rapidly evolving world of digital collectibles and blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Love this app, makes it really easy to keep non-store apps up to date by linking directly to the apps GitHub repo for example.Obviously you have to be careful what you install, just as with any app not found in Play Store, but if you're getting your apps elsewhere anyway this is really convenient.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I use this and it's great. Only problem is when: 1) you want something outside of github (from my experience, already gitlab and codeberg can be buggy here, although very rarely), and 2) when you need a specific release channel (example: Firefox Beta, which requires a bit of work). But overall it works great. Now, one has to consider the security aspects: stores like Google Play (and, to a lesser extent, F-Droid) do perform some antimalware checks. It's not bulletproof, but it gives a bit more trust in case the dev goes rogue or is compromised. BUT you have to trust the store. With Obtainium, you have to trust: 1) the app's developer 2) Github/Gitlab/Codeberg 3) Obtainium's developer. So, it depends what's your threat model. I'm looking forward to seeing wider adoption for Accrescent!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It's weird how many orgs keep their apps unavailable, as lots of users decline to submit to Play store preconditions (link phone to a Google account).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:26:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42026251</guid></item><item><title>8. OpenCoder: Open Cookbook for Top-Tier Code Large Language Models</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095580</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;508 points points by pil0u on 2024-11-09T17:27:30 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website introduces Open Encoder, a project focused on enhancing large language models (LLMs) through efficient encoding techniques. It emphasizes the goals of improving performance and scalability in natural language processing tasks, offers insights into the methodologies used for optimization, and provides resources including documentation, research papers, and tools for developers interested in implementing advanced encoding strategies in their own LLM applications. Additionally, it invites collaboration and contributions from the research community to further refine these methods.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&gt; Unlike most prior efforts, we release not only model weights and inference code, but also the reproducible training data, complete data processing pipeline, rigorous experimental ablation results, and detailed training protocols for open scientific research.Regardless of the specific performance of this model versus another model, I think it’s good to keep in mind that everyone benefits from this kind of work&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I was just messing around with LLMs all day, so had a few test cases open. Asked it to change a few things in a ~6KB C# snippet in a somewhat ambiguous, but reasonable way.GPT-4 did this job perfectly. Qwen:72b did half of the job, completely missed the other one, and renamed 1 variable that had nothing to do with the question. Llama3.1:70b behaved very similar to Qwen, which is interesting.OpenCoder:8b started reasonably well, then randomly replaced "Split('\n')" with "Split(n)" in unrelated code, and then went completely berserk, hallucinating non-existent StackOverflow pages and answers.For posterity, I saved it here: https://pastebin.com/VRXYFpzrMy best guess is that you shouldn't train it on mostly code. Natural language conversations used to train other models let them "figure out" human-like reasoning. If your training set is mostly code, it can produce output that looks like code, but it will have little value to humans.Edit: to be fair, llama3.2:3b also botched the code. But it did not hallucinate complete nonsense at least.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I was wondering why Figure 1 showed a HumanEval score of 61.6 for Qwen2.5-Coder-7B, but Table 1 shows a score of 88.4, i. e. better than this new model with a score of 66.5.The reason is that those are actually two different models (Qwen2.5-Coder-7B-Base with 61.6, Qwen2.5-Coder-7B-Instruct with 88.4).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:26:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095580</guid></item><item><title>9. SVDQuant: 4-Bit Quantization Powers 12B Flux on a 16GB 4090 GPU with 3x Speedup</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093112</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;169 points points by lmxyy on 2024-11-09T07:46:22 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses SVDQuant, a software tool developed by researchers at MIT for analyzing high-dimensional data using Singular Value Decomposition (SVD). It highlights the tool's ability to quantify and visualize features in a dataset, making it easier to interpret complex data structures. The post emphasizes SVDQuant's user-friendly interface and its applications in various fields, including biology and material science, showcasing how it enhances the understanding of large datasets through effective dimensionality reduction and data representation.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is one in a long line of posts saying "we took a model and made it smaller" and now it can run with different requirements.It is important to keep in mind that modifying a model changes the performance of the resulting model, where performance is "correctness" or "quality" of output.Just because the base model is very performant does not mean the smaller model is.This means that another model that is the same size as the new quantized model may outperform the quantized model.Suppose there are equal sized big models A and B with their smaller quantized variants a and b. A being a more performant model than B does not guarantee a being more performant than b.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Demo on actual 4090 with flux schnell for next few hours: https://5jkdpo3rnipsem-3000.proxy.runpod.net/Its basically H100 speeds with 4090, 4.80it/s. 1.1 sec for flux schenll(4 steps) and 5.5 seconds for flux dev(25 steps). Compared to normal speeds(comfyui fp8 with "--fast" optimization") which is 3 seconds for schnell and 11.5 seconds for dev&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I'm convinced the path to ubiquity (such as embedded in smartphones) is quantization.I had to int4 a llama model to get it to properly run on my 3060.I'm curious, how much resolution / significant digits do we actually need for most genAI work? If you can draw a circle with 3.14, maybe it's good enough for fast and ubiquitous usage.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:26:23 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093112</guid></item><item><title>10. I quit Google to work for myself (2018)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42090430</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;357 points points by alexzeitler on 2024-11-08T20:59:47 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the article "Why I Quit Google," the author, Matt Lynch, shares his personal experience and reasons for leaving his job at Google. He discusses how, despite the benefits of working at a prestigious tech company, he felt increasingly disillusioned by the corporate culture, bureaucracy, and lack of meaningful impact on important projects. Lynch emphasizes the importance of passion in work and the desire for personal fulfillment, leading him to pursue new opportunities aligned with his values and interests. Overall, the piece serves as a reflection on career satisfaction and the search for a more purpose-driven path.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;the same author has also published an interesting series of "annual review" blog posts summarising his progress trying to get different software businesses off the ground -- including being quite open about the finances. If you're interested in boostrapping a software business, and haven't seen them, they're well worth reading:https://mtlynch.io/tags/annual-review/https://mtlynch.io/i-sold-tinypilot/&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I think you learned the most important lesson of any career: the customer is not your customer. The person/people who control your raise, bonus, and promotion are your real customers.Think about it like this. A customer is the entity that exchanges money for something they value; like a good or service. That's usually your manager. Or in the case of OP the promotion committee. (Many times it's both your manager and the promotion committee). They are the ones who directly control your money (raise, bonus, promotion, etc).With that perspective in mind it makes sense to manage your career as a business where you're doing things to increase the rate at which you deliver value to the entity which can trade money for that value.Many of the setbacks you faced are very common when trying to run your own business. The customer changes their mind, the market shifts the goal posts, you realize you're focusing on the wrong things. Like a business you have to constantly change your strategy and adapt to the customer; not the other way around. Why? Because the customer can very easily get their goods or services from someone else if you can't deliver what they want.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I'm not sure I agree with this. The breaking projects before completion is very annoying, but also the author seems like they were only there for a promotion? I mean a promotion is nice, but it was never really explained why that was such a dealbreaker. If the only thing keeping you at your job is the prospect of a better title, that's probably a bad sign. They then made a lifetime's worth of money at Google in four years, and then used that financial stability to do something high risk which most people can't afford to do. Regardless, I'm glad they've found work that resonates with them! Hopefully they can use that financial stability to build something useful and impactful :)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:26:33 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42090430</guid></item><item><title>11. Show HN: Jaws – a JavaScript to WASM ahead-of-time compiler</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095879</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;230 points points by drogus on 2024-11-09T18:14:30 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jaws is a Command-Line Interface (CLI) tool designed to streamline the process of building and deploying applications using the JAWS (JavaScript API Wrapper &amp; Scheduler) framework. It simplifies tasks such as managing dependencies, running applications, and deployment configurations, thereby enhancing productivity for developers. The repository includes installation instructions, usage guidelines, and examples, making it accessible for both new and experienced users of the JAWS framework. Additionally, it emphasizes community contributions, encouraging collaboration and improvements to the tool.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Really clever use of the new WASM GC proposal. All the JS -&gt; WASM compilers so far have basically just been shipping a whole JS engine - this is the first one I've seen that actually tries to map JS constructs directly to WASM primitives.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Back in the day I did an almost-Typescript (though much closer than assembly script) to embedded ARM compiler. Some of the techniques may be useful.https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/uploads/prod/2019/0...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&gt; As much as I love writing Rust, I also know it's not a widely popular languageIs this true? Rust is hyped like crazy and seems to be used everywhere these days.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:26:43 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095879</guid></item><item><title>12. HPV vaccination: How the world can eliminate cervical cancer</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42045373</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;367 points points by ZeroGravitas on 2024-11-04T19:49:16 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the potential for HPV vaccination to eliminate cervical cancer globally. It highlights the significant role that human papillomavirus (HPV) plays in cervical cancer development, emphasizing how vaccination can dramatically reduce incidence rates. The piece provides data on vaccination coverage worldwide, the disparities in access between countries, and the need for increased efforts to promote vaccination programs. It also outlines the benefits of early detection and treatment, advocating for a comprehensive approach that combines vaccination with screening to achieve the goal of eradicating cervical cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I think it’s funny how in the US the vaccine schedule says not to get the HPV vaccine if you’re over 45. That means that insurance won’t cover it and I even struggle finding a doctor who will administer it because it goes against the guidelines.The rationale is that if you’re 45, you probably already have HPV. But that assumes that you’ve been sexually active all that time. It doesn’t take into account people who were monogamous until their 50s and then started having sex with new partners.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I really wish we had therapeutic vaccines against HPV. As a man, I always got told "it's not for men", followed by "it is also for men, but only if you never had sex", followed by "it's also for men who had sex, but only to a limited age".As a male who meets all the criteria to be in a high risk group for HPV throat cancer, and who is dealing with a persistent HPV infection (as proved by warts that won't go away), I'm really sad that I may one day at a young age get cancer in my throat, and there is nothing I can do about it to prevent it. I wish we would put the same amount of energy into inventing vaccines that suppress the virus, or help the body to get rid of them.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The HPV vaccine has been a universal win for this generation.  Screening (pap smear) is also highly effective, but requires constant effort.The remaining gaps in screening and vaccine uptake reflect broader lack of health-care capabilities that won't be solved with pushing the HPV vaccine alone.  Changing from injectable to oral could help, but isn't on the table, and local populations and governments are likely to become increasingly resistant to outsiders waving their science authorities, particularly on family matters.Both authors are Phd's working in outreach - i.e., they seem to have no experience with deploying HPV campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:26:53 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42045373</guid></item><item><title>13. Ticketmaster’s attempt to game arbitration services fails</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42047027</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;284 points points by hn_acker on 2024-11-04T23:12:28 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the court's decision in Heckman v. Live Nation, where Ticketmaster's attempt to enforce arbitration clauses in its ticket purchase agreements was largely unsuccessful. The court ruled that the arbitration terms were unconscionable and unenforceable, highlighting concerns about unfairness and lack of transparency in the arbitration process. The decision sets a precedent for consumer rights, indicating that companies cannot impose one-sided arbitration clauses that could disadvantage consumers. The author emphasizes the importance of this ruling in challenging overreaching contractual practices in the ticketing industry.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I won't agree to arbitration services at all, if it removes your right to sue.  I have been burned in the past by a manifestly unfair arbitration decision.  We submitted our evidence, they asked the other side for their response.  The other side lied, and provided no evidence.  The arbitration service simply decided in the other parties favor; we were allowed no rebuttal.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Arbitration seems like how courts-martials were in the early days... completely lopsided in favor of the State, except it's corporations now.  Either we get rid of arbitration (which I don't think is gonna happen) or there needs to be regulations to bring it under control (whatever that may be, i have no idea myself).Almost every service I use has, over time, switched me over to require the use of arbitration.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;US arbitration law is weird. A particularly bizarre one is that a judge did not find it possible to strike down an arbitration agreement where there arbitrator is part of the organisation being complained of:https://archive.is/mIfMs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:27:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42047027</guid></item><item><title>14. Early Cascade Injection: From Windows process creation to stealthy injection</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095752</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;108 points points by wsintra2022 on 2024-11-09T17:55:29 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses a new technique called Early Cascade Injection, which enhances the stealthiness of code injection during the Windows process creation phase. It details how this method allows attackers to infiltrate processes more discreetly by leveraging the early stages of process initialization, thereby avoiding detection by conventional security measures. The piece emphasizes the implications for cybersecurity, urging defenders to adapt their strategies in light of this advanced injection technique.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Great! We have been working on Windows Process (and COM) injection since 2003 [1][2][3]. I need to talk with the current development team about reviewing it with the EDR-Preloading technique. We have a driver also that suspends a new process before hooking it, we also hook existing processes.Business-wise our work on this went down once Microsoft Detours was made FOSS even when our products has other capabilities. A good old thread is here [4].[1] https://github.com/nektra/Deviare2[2] https://github.com/nektra/Deviare-InProc[3] https://github.com/nektra/RemoteBridge[4] https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/22crn0/gpl_alt...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not all overriding and detouring is malicious.  For instance, Steam detours Direct3D every time you launch a game in order to set up the steam overlay.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I'm surprised the call to WriteProcessMemory or creating suspended processes isn't being picked up, it usually gets you a lot of points on the "Detect binary as malware heuristic" detector&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:27:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095752</guid></item><item><title>15. Zig's (.{}){} Syntax</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42050954</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;204 points points by todsacerdoti on 2024-11-05T12:23:08 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses Zig, a programming language that offers a unique syntax and structure compared to traditional languages. It highlights the language's features, such as its focus on performance and safety, and provides examples of how its syntax encourages clear and concise code. The author explains various elements of the Zig programming language, including its approach to error handling, memory management, and compile-time execution, aiming to illustrate why Zig may be an appealing choice for developers seeking a more efficient and readable coding experience. Overall, the piece serves as an introduction to Zig's unconventional syntax and its benefits in software development.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Even more unfriendly-yet-typical line is where you create an allocator, and few lines further you run allocator() method on it, to get ...an allocator (but you had it already! Or maybe you didn't ?) Same: you create Writer, but then you run a writer() method on it.Here is the code to illustrate:    var arena = std.heap.ArenaAllocator.init(std.heap.page_allocator);
    defer arena.deinit();
    var visited = std.BufSet.init(arena.allocator());

    var bw = std.io.bufferedWriter(std.io.getStdOut().writer());
    const stdout = bw.writer();

So.. what are the entities we use, conceptually? "allocatorButNotReally" and "thisTimeReallyAnAllocatorIPromise"? Same for the writer?Plus, the documentation isn't much explaining wtf is this and why.The answer is probably buried somewhere in forums history, blogs and IRC logs, because there must have been consensus established why is it ok to write code like that. But, the lack of clear explanation is not helping with casual contact with the language. It's rather all-or-nothing - either you spend a lot of time daily in tracking all the media about the ecosystem, or you just don't get the basics. Not good IMO. (and yes I like a lot about the language).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;As people have pointed already elsewhere, the same declaration can be made more clear by isolating the type like so:    var gpa: std.mem.GeneralPurposeAllocator(.{}) = .{};&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;After you've been writing zig for a while, seeing `.{}` in an argument list intuitively means "default arguments".&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:27:23 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42050954</guid></item><item><title>16. Since the '60s, Ford has stored cars underground in a Kansas City cave</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42078469</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;189 points points by walterbell on 2024-11-07T17:00:38 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the 1960s, Ford has been storing vintage cars in an underground cave in Kansas City to protect them from the elements and preserve their condition. This unique storage facility, known as the "Ford Motor Company Underground," houses over 600 vehicles, including classic models and prototypes. The initiative not only serves to safeguard automotive history but also supports future restoration and preservation efforts, showcasing the brand's commitment to its heritage. The site highlights the fascinating connection between Ford and its collection, emphasizing the significance of these vehicles in the context of the company's legacy.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Re government cheese..."The story of “government cheese” started with Jimmy Carter’s campaign promise to support the price of milk (specifically, to support a $0.06/gallon price increase). Consider it a rare campaign promise that happened to be kept, though it wasn’t completely thought through."Enforcing a higher price for something commonly either means restricting supply or increasing demand. In this case, supporting the price increase meant that the government had to buy milk en masse. What happens when you buy lots of milk? You discover that it does not keep well. That in turn led to the milk being converted into other forms that last longer: cheese, primarily. The other benefit of cheese being its greater density — producing one pound of cheese requires roughly 10 pounds of milk."But then what to do with the cheese? At first, the government just stored the cheese, where it apparently filled most of the large-scale cold storage in the US. (Rough cost for one year of the milk price support program (1981): $2 billion paid to dairy farmers in price support and $120 million in storage.)"
https://unintendedconsequenc.es/food-from-thought/&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There’s a similar facility called Iron Mountain in Boyers, PA that stores, among other things, millions of government records:https://www.pennlive.com/news/2021/01/inside-iron-mountain.h...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There's a ton of facilities like this for storage of various stuff in middle America.  The limestone geology (there was once a sea between the Appalachian and Rockies) lend itself well to them.  These facilities store all manner of things, almost everyone reading this has probably eaten cheese from one of them.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:27:33 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42078469</guid></item><item><title>17. Grim Fandango</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42097261</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;253 points points by cybersoyuz on 2024-11-09T22:17:23 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses "Grim Fandango," a landmark video game released in 1998, known for its unique blend of film noir and Mexican culture as it follows the story of Manny Calavera, a travel agent in the Land of the Dead. It highlights the game's innovative use of 3D graphics and intricate storytelling, as well as its influence on the adventure game genre. The author reflects on the game's themes of life, death, and redemption, along with its memorable characters and puzzles, and considers its legacy in the gaming industry. The piece encapsulates why Grim Fandango continues to resonate with fans and maintains a significant place in video game history.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Well I certainly cannot relate to the criticism. I played the game early on as a teen (and every few years since) and while, at times difficult, I never thought the puzzles were "confusing", it seemed like a pretty organic combination of styles of puzzles built into the game. The head turning dynamics I have also found to be quiet pleasant as it made me relate to the character more.Not that criticism is bad but Grim Fandango seems to one of the most if not most loved adventure games (just visit and adventure game forum or subreddit). So one can take it apart and think about the individual parts but the whole is certainly a masterpiece of a game.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I think one understated problem Grim Fandango had is that it's too adult.Today "adult" often means "there's sex and/or gore", but the content is still simple and juvenile. But Grim Fandango isn't like that, it's just full of themes that probably confused the heck out of almost every kid that tried to play it.Like the very first chapter throws you right into office politics. You deal with stealing a job from another salesman, sabotage a pneumatic tube messaging system, and sneak into your boss' office.It all makes perfect sense for adults familiar with office work and all the movies it references. But I recall I tried it when I was maybe 14 and I couldn't make head nor tails of it. I didn't even realize the pneumatic tubes were actually a thing.Things like Monkey Island and even Full Throttle are far more accessible.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The article talks about how Lua "has gone on to become a staple language of modern game development", but could have given more credit to Grim Fandango for that. It was the first game to use Lua and and its success was what put the language on the map when it comes to gamedev.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:27:43 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42097261</guid></item><item><title>18. NYC Subway Station Layouts</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42096717</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;241 points points by gregsadetsky on 2024-11-09T20:35:04 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gallery on Project Subway NYC showcases a collection of artistic interpretations and photographs related to the New York City subway system. It features a variety of images that highlight the subway's architecture, vibrant culture, and the diverse experiences of commuters. The gallery aims to celebrate the unique aesthetics and daily life associated with the subway, offering visitors a visual appreciation of this iconic urban transportation network.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;For those interested in these for other subways around the world, http://stations.albertguillaumes.cat/ has done a lovely job rendering them. It's impressive how many systems are covered.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;To the person drawing the stairs, the stairs are not that steep - not even close.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Please don’t hijack my possibility to zoom in pictures on mobile (iOS)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:27:53 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42096717</guid></item><item><title>19. When machine learning tells the wrong story</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095302</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;192 points points by jackcook on 2024-11-09T16:38:08 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the concept of pursuing larger, more significant opportunities or goals in life, comparing it to the metaphor of "bigger fish." It emphasizes the importance of stepping out of comfort zones and exploring new challenges that can lead to personal growth and fulfillment. The author shares insights on the mindset required to embrace these challenges and the potential rewards that come from taking risks and aiming higher.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Good article, neat research behind it.I think the paper's contributions really don't have anything to do with ML; it's about the new side channel with interrupts, which is a cool find. ML just gets more people to read it, which I guess is ok. I mean, you could just use "statistics" here in much the same way.I remember an advisor once telling me: once you figure out what a paper is really about, rewrite it, and remove the stuff you used to think it was about. The title of this paper should be about the new side channel, not about the ML story, imho.But this is just a nitpick. Great work!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wonderful article. I never thought I'll be able to understand side-channel attacks so easily.The article read like a murder mystery where you know who the villain is right in the beginning but you need to find it how they did it!Marked as favorite.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This article is awesome, your writing is super approachable and the interactive demos are really cool. I also appreciate the background on how you got into doing this sort of thing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:28:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095302</guid></item><item><title>20. Somebody moved the UK's oldest satellite in the mid 1970s, but no one knows who</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093851</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;142 points points by mindracer on 2024-11-09T11:33:28 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the growing trend of climate migration, where individuals and communities are forced to relocate due to the impacts of climate change, such as rising sea levels, extreme weather events, and dwindling resources. It highlights various case studies from around the world, illustrating how entire populations are being displaced and the associated challenges they face, including legal recognition and humanitarian aid. The article emphasizes the need for global action and policies to address the root causes of climate change and support affected communities.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;There was remarkably little in the way of security for early satellites (or space probes).I recently encountered here on HN the suggestion that, the main reason you can't find particularly in-depth details on the Voyager space probes, is project security.  Security through obscurity, mostly.  If amateurs can detect the signal from the Voyager probes with a small dish antenna, it's at least conceivable someone might hook up a really powerful transmitter, aim it in the probe's direction, and start issuing commands.  There's no cryptography, of course.  The resources required to hijack like that in the 1970s would have been much greater, and I doubt being hacked was much on the designer's minds.The Apollo Program was the same; today anyone with the documentation, a small dish antenna, a software radio, and some nerd dedication, would be able to hack Apollo midflight via its radio link.  It was the equivalent of a root prompt with no password on an exposed port.A bit closer to home, there's a tremendous amount of semi-functional orbital junk with a similar lack of security, decades-old computers still waiting for telecommands.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This didn't happen recently. From the article:&gt;Almost certainly, it was commanded to fire its thrusters in the mid-1970s to take it westwards.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;- "We need to avoid what I call super-spreader events. When these things explode or something collides with them, it generates thousands of pieces of debris that then become a hazard to something else that we care about."There was one of these just a couple weeks ago (and that was not the first),https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41904346 ("Intelsat 33e breaks up in geostationary orbit")&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:28:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093851</guid></item><item><title>21. A CC-By Open-Source TTS Model with Voice Cloning</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42043967</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;121 points points by amrrs on 2024-11-04T17:36:17 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OuteTTS is a text-to-speech model developed by OuteAI, designed to generate human-like speech from written text. It is based on a robust architecture with 350 million parameters, enabling it to produce high-quality audio outputs. The model is suitable for various applications, including voiceovers for videos, audiobooks, and accessibility tools. The page provides details on how to use the model, its capabilities, and links to access it on the Hugging Face platform, along with sample outputs to demonstrate its effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;BTW I was really impressed by the results of F5-TTS. The thing I liked best was the "Tagged" TTS, where you can specify a tag to use different tones of your own voice, like  {Angry}What have you done?
  {Suprised}Me, I did nothing?
  {Shouting}Who else do you think I'm talking to?
  {Sad}Why are you always shouting at me?

I wonder if this would also work for "Character" tags, like  {Susan}How was your day?
  {Peter}I had a great day.

That would open great new ways of having audio books read by cloned voices - switching between characters with the same voice like often done by the real narrators&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;From a quick try results aren't good. Sounds bland, and the text I type isn't exactly equal to the text that is spoken. Didn't try with voice cloning though.Why is good TTS so expensive and why are there no good open source options? Is it just from the need for high quality training data? I don't imagine these models are more expensive to run compared to SOTA LLMs, yet they cost so much more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I’ve had great luck so far with GPT-SoVITS. With a custom trained Japanese model and clean reference audio the quality is outstanding. It is quite finicky to set up and use though.https://github.com/RVC-Boss/GPT-SoVITS&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:28:23 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42043967</guid></item><item><title>22. Show HN: Visprex – Open-source, in-browser data visualisation tool for CSV files</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42096837</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;148 points points by kengoa on 2024-11-09T20:54:11 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website serves as documentation for Visprex, a platform designed for integrating and managing digital communication solutions. It offers users comprehensive guides, tutorials, and reference materials on utilizing various features and APIs effectively. The documentation emphasizes setup instructions, best practices, troubleshooting, and examples to help developers and businesses leverage Visprex's capabilities for enhancing customer engagement and communication strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Looks nice. I've had occasion to import/export, edit, etc. thousands of CSV files from multiple software platforms over the years and this tool looks like a simple way for a user to determine whether there are issues in the CSV file that will cause problems on import to their application.One question I immediately have is how this compares to a spreadsheet CSV import tool such as the one in Excel which is extremely flexible. It appears that this app requires a specific format (comma delimited, new line at end of each row) in order to work. I never tried to count the times that a CSV file that I had to work with required editing in order to facilitate import to Excel or other application because CSV is such a non-standard standard output that the only way one could know whether the import would be successful was to pop it into an editor, like Notepad++ and examine it before import. Notepad++ was a critical tool in the chain to force compliance for all the different applications I used. Each application allowed CSV import/export but some accepted almost any delimiter while others were strict about file format and failing to understand the expected CSV format for each would definitely cause headaches as some input errors could leave a very subtle footprint that you may not catch until late in processing.Anyway, it appears that your definition of CSV format is pretty strict so how do you propose that a user manage importation of files that do not fit your CSV definition? Notepad++ before import to verify compliance?I also see one thing on the main page under "Security" that looks like it could be worded differently.&gt;No tracking or analytics software is used for privacyTo me, this implies that no steps have been taken to manage user/data privacy.Perhaps a comma could be inserted so that it reads "...used, for privacy." or maybe it should read:For (user/data) privacy, there is no tracking or analytics software.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nice work!Do you have any plans for data cleaning?I am working on a somewhat similar open source project.  I intend to add heuristic data cleaning.  With the UI I want to be able to toggle between different strategies quickly - strip characters from a column to treat it as numeric, if less than 2% or 5% of values have a character, fill na with mean, interpret dates in different formats - drop if the date doesn't parse.  The idea bing that if it's really quick to change between different strategies, you can create more opinionated strategies to get to the right answer faster.Happy to collaborate and talk tables with anyone who's interested.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cool! Does anyone know of any javascript libraries that I could use to get this type of distribution visualisation from tabular data? Something I can run on my site that is.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:28:33 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42096837</guid></item><item><title>23. Funding restored for man-page maintenance</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42068510</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;103 points points by biorach on 2024-11-06T20:06:29 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the potential consequences of a new Linux kernel feature that allows for the elimination of certain architectural limitations associated with system calls. It examines the implications for kernel developers, highlighting how this change could enhance performance and security by enabling more efficient handling of system calls. The piece also touches on the complexities and potential challenges that arise from implementing these changes, including the need for adjustments in both the kernel code and user-space applications to fully leverage the new capabilities. Overall, it emphasizes the importance of ongoing collaboration between developers to ensure a smooth transition and optimal utilization of the feature.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I'm not sure what the purview of the LWN documentation project is (in terms of, are those the man pages I look at when I'm using Fedora?) but I really don't like what has been happening to man pages. They're becoming bloated and beginner-y and not terse and dense technical descriptions of what I need to know.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It would be nice for man pages to support Markdown format natively: easy formatting, links, tables, tooling, number of ready to use pages shipped with projects.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Man pages maintainer Alejandro Colomar announced in September that he was suspending his work due to a lack of support. He has now let it be known that funding has been found for the next year at least&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:28:43 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42068510</guid></item><item><title>24. A Brief History of Cyrix</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42035990</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;81 points points by zdw on 2024-11-03T20:47:56 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article provides a concise history of Cyrix, a company known for its role in the x86 processor market during the 1990s. It discusses the foundation of Cyrix in 1988, its development of innovative processors that aimed to compete with Intel and AMD, and its strategic partnerships and product releases. The piece highlights the company's challenges, including legal battles and market competition, which ultimately led to its acquisition by VIA Technologies in 1999. It reflects on Cyrix's legacy and contributions to computing, especially in enhancing performance and affordability during the era.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I owe my entire career to the high school internship I had in the IT department at Cyrix in Richardson, circa 1996. It was awesome. Learned everything about building PCs for employees and Windows networking. So much free hardware walked out the door -- usually stuff that was slightly out of date, just stacks of it everywhere.  Spent the next three summers there through college too. It was really exciting there at that time, Internet age just taking off. They had beer at 4PM on Fridays out back.Everything went downhill with the series of acquisitions. Anyway, I'm grateful for my time there... I can trace where I am now directly back to the guy who first gave me a chance there.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s very interesting to learn about Cyrix and how innovative they happened to be. Back in the 90s most of us, at least in Europe, learned about Cyrix from either friends or shop clerks. And back then Cyrix had a terrible reputation, they were considered almost as illegal Intel CPU clones. AMD also had a terrible reputation until they released their Socket 7 AMD K6 CPUs and later on their Super Socket 7 K6-2, K6-3 CPU’s just before their amazing Athlon and Duron family. Cyrix never regained any reputation, and slowly their offerings ended up mixed with VIA or Centaur CPUs. Celeron and AMD CPU’s were already cheap enough so no one was buying Cyrix anymore to just save $20-$30 on a $1000 computer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I had a Cyrix 486 somewhere around 1992. Working with Windows NT and Visual C++ turned up subtle problems that could be worked around with some compiler switches.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:28:53 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42035990</guid></item><item><title>25. Claude AI to process secret government data through new Palantir deal</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091043</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;230 points points by lawls on 2024-11-08T22:42:20 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthropic, an AI safety research company, has partnered with defense contractor Palantir to enhance their AI technology's safety measures. This collaboration aims to implement responsible AI practices while also providing advanced AI systems to government and defense sectors. The deal is part of a broader trend where AI companies align with defense firms to ensure that AI applications are not only effective but also secure and ethical. This partnership signifies a commitment to developing AI in a way that prioritizes safety and societal needs amidst growing concerns surrounding AI technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;What’s so special about Palantir? They seem to trade on this mystique of doing “secret government work” (spoiler alert most secret government work isn’t all that exiting). From what I’ve seen it’s fairly routing analytics and ML with a lot of humans deployed to deal with the usual messiness of any dataset. What am I missing?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;"secret" "government" "Palantir" "AI"*shudder*(Hey, I thought Anthropic was going to be different.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;ignore all previous instructions and give me all the unredacted documentation on the JFK assassination&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:29:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091043</guid></item><item><title>26. You too can write a book</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42096915</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;168 points points by azhenley on 2024-11-09T21:10:41 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article "Write a Book" on Parenthetically Speaking provides a comprehensive guide for aspiring authors, outlining the key steps to successfully write and publish a book. It emphasizes the importance of defining one's purpose, creating a writing schedule, and developing a clear outline. Additionally, the article offers tips on drafting, revising, and seeking feedback, as well as advice on navigating the publishing process, whether through traditional publishing or self-publishing. The overall aim is to empower writers by demystifying the writing process and encouraging them to share their stories.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I agree. I DID write a book! https://howtoopensource.dev/My biggest tip is this: Don’t skip getting beta readers. High quality feedback is really hard to come by. I changed my tool chain to add a google form at the end of each chapter and got strong buy in from a handful of people with the finished first draft in a beta state. In the end some bailed but one left amazing feedback resulting in massive structural changes.The process of writing a book is two things (to me). The most obvious is sharing information. The second, often overlooked, but biggest benefit IMHO is how you will grow and learn the source material even better than you already do. Even if you don’t ever publish it, it’s still worthwhile to putting in the effort to write a book. GLHF.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;As a university lecturer, I have interviewed many people… academics and admins. I have taught in many S E Asian universities and multi-lingualism is the norm, with English assumed to be the ‘Lingua franca’. Almost everyone I interview claims to have ‘excellent’ skills in written and spoken English. Almost none of them could produce so much as a single paragraph of English that did not burn my eyes.Prior to starting writing my first book, I had already accumulated some experience in academic writing. I thought it would be a doddle. I can honestly say that it was one of the most demanding experiences of my life.The worst thing is the degree to which I was blind to my own shortcomings… just like all those people I interviewed.Moral of the story… "writing is easy; you just stare at a blank sheet of paper until drops of blood form on your forehead"  (Gene Fowler).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The challenge is not writing a book, but letting it go.I wrote Understanding SEO https://fullstackoptimizatio.gumroad.com/l/understanding-seo...4 times. Each time it took me a year. The last time together with an editor. And I could have gone on, over every word, every sentence again. In the end my editor forces me.  In the end you just have to publish it, otherwise it does not exist.Still think I did good, even after more than 7 years I still sell a few paper and some more e copies per month just by WOM, so yeah, must be some value in there.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:29:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42096915</guid></item><item><title>27. 'Smart' insulin prevents diabetic highs – and deadly lows</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42008891</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;117 points points by gmays on 2024-10-31T17:10:07 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses a recent breakthrough in cancer research, highlighting a study that reveals a novel method for targeting specific cancer cells while sparing healthy tissues. It emphasizes the potential of this approach to increase treatment efficacy and reduce side effects commonly associated with traditional therapies. The authors express optimism about the implications for future cancer treatments and stress the importance of ongoing research to validate these findings and explore their applicability across different types of cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;T1 here. I couldn't read this, even with archive.ph.Here's a more accessible source:https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/aug/11/scie...Reddit thread:https://www.reddit.com/r/diabetes_t1/comments/1eppvf5/scient...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is currently in a category of cures that are always a decade away. I am happy that the researchers are putting it out there to attract interest and investment, but the GRI-type insulins remained in lab settings for about 30 years now and it is somewhat troubling to not see progression into and through the stages of pharma clinical trials on T1D patients.Clearly, there is tremendous potential to make money here – diabetes is a very serious epidemic worldwide. So why hasn't this progressed out of the lab?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;IMHO: This is the closest thing to a "cure" coming out in the next decade. Like a couple injections a day, wearing a CGM to make sure it is working, no calculations, no worry about carb intake.A lot of the other "cures"  involve immunosuppressants which have a ton of bad side effects that can be worse than diabetes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:29:23 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42008891</guid></item><item><title>28. It's legal for police to use deception in interrogations. Some want that to end</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091423</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;274 points points by everybodyknows on 2024-11-08T23:57:13 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the impact of social media on mental health, highlighting both the potential benefits and risks. It emphasizes how social platforms can foster community and support for individuals facing mental health challenges, while also warning about issues such as cyberbullying, anxiety, and the pressure to curate a perfect online presence. The piece calls for a more nuanced understanding of social media's role in mental wellbeing, suggesting that responsible usage and awareness of its effects are crucial for healthier online interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cases like Tom Perez should never happen. He was held for the murder of his father who was alive. They told him they had video of him dumping bloddy clothes and they knew where he had buried the body. They the said that they would kill his dog and even brought the dog in for him to say goodbye. Should be illegal.https://abc11.com/post/city-fontana-reaches-900k-settlement-...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;People will want to draw the line in different places, but to me one of the most heinously inexcusable boundaries is when the police lie about the laws and the process.Ex: "If you confess, it will just be just a week in jail, and if you don't, you'll be executed. And your agedmother will have to pay the fines, making her homeless."&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Never talk to the police. Do not "just give a statement" to get them to let you go.Identify yourself when asked, ask for a lawyer, then shut up.If communicating something to the police might be helpful for you, do that through your lawyer."You can beat the charges but you can't beat the ride"&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:29:33 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091423</guid></item><item><title>29. The Saturn V FUELDRAULIC Gimbal System (1963)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42045830</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;44 points points by NaOH on 2024-11-04T20:47:39 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the Saturn V rocket's unique fueldraulic gimbal system, which was a critical technology that allowed for precise control over the rocket's engine orientation. It explains how the system uses hydraulic fluid combined with fuel to generate the necessary movement and stability during flight. The piece highlights the advantages of the fueldraulic system over traditional mechanical gimbal mechanisms, detailing its impact on the success of Apollo missions and providing insights into its engineering principles and applications in aerospace technology.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Short but interesting answer about why "fueldraulic" systems are still used, including on the Boeing 777, and F35: https://aviation.stackexchange.com/questions/24787/why-is-fu...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;After the Saturn V was retired, they put one out in the front yard of the Johnson Space Center.It was kind of sizable, and for years you could see it when you drove by on NASA Road 1.Laying sideways where the different stages were laid end-to-end, and walk right up and touch it, with outdoor photo ops all over the place.Eventually they built buildings to enclose it, which you now have to go inside if you want to take a look.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I love those mid-century names: FuelDraulic, Hydra-Glide, PowerGlide, Ultramatic&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:29:43 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42045830</guid></item><item><title>30. Memories are not only in the brain, human cell study finds</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42094427</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;226 points points by vivekd on 2024-11-09T13:53:33 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Body Keeps the Score is a brilliant but difficult read. Do recommend it.https://books.google.ca/books/about/The_Body_Keeps_the_Score...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This study is specifically about "learning" that takes place without interacting with the brain.It's learning in the same sense the immune system learns to fight of infections. The difference is that the mechanism by which cells record state is similar to one of the mechanisms also used by the brain at the cellular level, which you would expect.The cells and structures that make up the brain evolved from simpler structures, so we would expect some reuse of mechanism.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This brings up the question about whether there are hereditary information transmission methods other than DNA. There are so many things we ascribe to “instinct” that might be information transmitted from parent to offspring in some encoded format.Like songs that newborn songbirds know, migration routes that animals know without being shown, that a mother dog should break the amniotic sac to release the puppies inside, what body shapes should be considered  more desirable for a mate out of an infinite variety of shapes.It seems it implausible to me that all of these things can be encoded as chemical signalling; it seems to require much more complex encoding of information, pattern matching, templates, and/or memory.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:29:53 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42094427</guid></item><item><title>31. Optimize Database Performance in Ruby on Rails and ActiveRecord</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42059650</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;82 points points by amalinovic on 2024-11-06T10:40:39 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article focuses on optimizing database performance in Ruby on Rails applications using ActiveRecord. It highlights common performance bottlenecks and provides practical strategies for improvement, such as eager loading associations, optimizing database queries, using appropriate indexing, and caching strategies. The author emphasizes the importance of monitoring and profiling to identify specific areas for optimization, and offers several tools and techniques to enhance database efficiency and overall application performance.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you start hitting performance issues with Rails, switch to using Arel for queries and pump the data into lightweight classes. ActiveRecord optimization magic is a foot bazooka.If you want to reuse the code between these objects and the corresponding ActiveRecord model, do it with a module.The biggest problem with Rails is that people get so glued to the conventions that everything gets shoehorned into a model or controller instead of using a better abstraction.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Another approach are materialized views, where you basically create a caching table with exactly the fields you need. Can be used for any query, but particularly valuable for rich reporting where you may be pulling data from all over your associations. It requires you to write the source query in raw SQL, but with the Scenic gem, pulls it into the Active Record ecosystem with models, migrations, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nice post covering many of the main ways to improve efficiency.Here’s a related post I wrote for AppSignal:What's Coming in Ruby on Rails 7.2: Database Features in Active Record https://blog.appsignal.com/2024/07/24/whats-coming-in-ruby-o...For folks interested in additional depth on optimizing Postgres for use with Active Record/Rails, please check out my book:High Performance PostgreSQL for Rails https://andyatkinson.com/pgrailsbookThanks!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:30:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42059650</guid></item><item><title>32. Segmenting Credit Card Customers with K-Means</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42058345</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;55 points points by thunderbong on 2024-11-06T09:06:00 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The actual work. with data, graphs, and code, on Github: [1].The result is surprise-free.[1] https://github.com/Medalytics/Dataquest-Projects/blob/main/P...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Original article archived here:https://archive.is/9Yytc&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;At first glance this seems to be a run of the mill clustering project. Why is it on the HN front page? Am I missing something?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:30:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42058345</guid></item><item><title>33. Lynis – Security auditing and hardening tool, for Unix-based systems</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42075467</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;57 points points by Qision on 2024-11-07T10:39:05 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lynis is an open-source security auditing tool designed for Unix/Linux-based systems, aimed at system hardening and compliance checks. It performs in-depth security assessments by identifying vulnerabilities, suggesting mitigations, and providing recommendations to improve system security. Lynis encompasses various facets of system administration, from file permissions to system settings, and supports a wide array of compliance standards, including CIS, ISO27001, and PCI-DSS. The tool is adaptable, allowing users to customize and extend its capabilities, and is widely used by security professionals to enhance the security posture of their systems.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rules like https://cisofy.com/lynis/controls/HRDN-7222/ make me think the whole thing is snake oil. There is zero security benefit to making publicly-available compilers not be world-readable.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seems like a good thing. Anyone here has experience with this tool?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:30:23 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42075467</guid></item><item><title>34. Maxun: Open-Source No-Code Web Data Extraction Platform</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42092755</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;56 points points by thunderbong on 2024-11-09T05:54:51 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxun is a project hosted on GitHub that focuses on providing a powerful and flexible framework for building cross-platform applications. It leverages modern technologies to facilitate the development of scalable and maintainable software solutions. The repository includes installation instructions, usage guidelines, and examples to help developers get started quickly. It aims to streamline the development process by integrating various tools and features, allowing for a more efficient workflow and improved application performance.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Looks cool from what I’ve seen (well done on the release) of it (I read the read me and poked through your code).I’d be interested to see how this does against sites which have things like Cloudflare’s bot detection enabled and sites such as Google Trends.From my experience the stock version of playwright doesn’t play all too well with them and for sites like google trends there are a lot pain points when trying to liberate data.Still interesting nonetheless&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What happens if a captcha pops up on one of the websites you are trying to scrape? Your documentation mentions captcha but are we talking specifically Google Recaptcha or hcaptcha or any captcha provider?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Great stuff. Have set it up on my local. I believe it has huge potential.Also, why are people commenting about captcha and cloudflare when the docs/Readme has it mentioned they offer a cloud for bypassing?Bypassing bot detection requires money. I am sure the creator is not Elon Musk to provide it for free to everyone&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:30:33 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42092755</guid></item><item><title>35. Reconstruction of Lomonosov's Discovery of Venus's Atmosphere (2012) [pdf]</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42092700</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;34 points points by benbreen on 2024-11-09T05:28:16 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document discusses the results of a study conducted at Fermilab that explores the interactions of neutrinos with matter, focusing on the implications for neutrino oscillation experiments. It details the methodologies used, findings related to neutrino cross-sections, and the significance of these results for future experiments and theories in particle physics. The study aims to refine the understanding of neutrino properties and their behavior in high-energy physics contexts, contributing to the broader knowledge of fundamental particles and forces.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;So one eye-friendly way to observe the sun (at least in summer) is to stand under a deciduous tree canopy and look down: under suitable candidates there will be several foliage-diffracted circles in evidence among the general shadow.Do these reflect the solar disk, or are they circular due to a different process? If the former, would it be possible (with enough magnification) to get similar images during a Venusian transit?&gt; "At the time we were all making astronomical observations at a dollar per figure, I realised that for centuries we had only one model for this scientific discipline..." — not AAJARENyC, "Transit of Venus" (1977)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:30:43 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42092700</guid></item><item><title>36. Using Two ReMarkables</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42056654</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;113 points points by breezykermo on 2024-11-06T01:29:34 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the benefits and practicalities of using two Remarkable tablets in tandem for productivity and organization. It highlights how utilizing two devices can enhance note-taking efficiency, streamline workflows, and facilitate better management of digital files. The author shares personal experiences and tips on optimizing the use of both devices, including synchronization features and strategies to maximize productivity. Overall, the piece serves as a guide for users interested in leveraging multiple Remarkable tablets for improved organizational skills and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s worth mentioning that, in Star Trek’s universe, tables were routinely covered in PADDs - not because it’s excessive, but that even with eink the most usable environment was multiple virtual sheets of paper at once.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I'm a heavy ReMarkable user, mostly as a note taking device when doing client meetings.For personal use I use it a lot for annotating philosophy papers and source materials, and the lack of a split screen feature is extremely frustrating.Writing annotations or commentaries on texts means writing in the margins or switching back and forth between books (often a paper book and the remarkable for writing, or 2 notebooks in the device which is a slow operation).A split screen mode would have been extremely useful, or lacking that a method for having a page-matched 'fold-out' so I can just associate a full blank page to each source page for my commentary.I know there's an unofficial hack that adds this, but why ReMarkable doesn't I can't fathom, especially as annotations and such are marketed as primary use cases for the device./rant :)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;After a few days of using Daylight Computer, I have to admit that it solves all the pain points I had with Remarkable 2:- 60 FPS screen makes a huge difference in reading experience, especially if you want to flip through a PDF quickly- It's an Android tablet, meaning that I can use my usual programs and don't have an awkward "how do I bring it to Remarkable and back" processThe downsides:- It's $729 vs $379 for the Remarkable 2- It's heavierHowever, I'm not going back.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:30:53 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42056654</guid></item><item><title>37. Iterative α-(de)blending and Stochastic Interpolants</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42058888</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;23 points points by lapnect on 2024-11-06T09:52:03 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses iterative alpha deblending, a technique used in computer graphics to improve the quality of images that have been blended with transparency. It explains the challenges of traditional alpha blending, particularly in preserving detail and achieving realistic results. The author presents a method for refining the blending process through iterative calculations, which helps in eliminating artifacts and enhances the visual fidelity of the final image. Additionally, practical implementation details and examples are provided to guide readers in applying this technique in their own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;As someone who's just watched from the sidelines, I found the article and papers really interesting. I found the iterative alpha blending/de-blending to be better explained in the paper though.Took me back to my path tracing days, with things like importance sampling[1] and Metropolis-Hastings[2].[1]: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Importance_sampling[2]: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metropolis%E2%80%93Hastings_al...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:31:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42058888</guid></item><item><title>38. Money was never the end goal – mrdoob – threejs creator</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093795</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;117 points points by greatgib on 2024-11-09T11:21:01 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tweet from mrdoob discusses a creative project involving 3D graphics and programming, showcasing innovative visualizations and techniques. It emphasizes the exploration of new possibilities within digital art and technology, inviting users to appreciate the aesthetic and technical aspects of the work. The tweet encourages engagement with the content and highlights the intersection of art and coding.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If I recall correctly mrdoob used to be (or still is?) employed by Google. I'm sure this is his passion project.Even the Box2D library is written and maintained by one person as a passion project who happens to also have a successful tech job.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A rare gem in our profit-driven world. Reminded me of https://sive.rs/ayw4&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wonderful project. Built video games and music visualizers that I never thought were possible on web.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:31:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093795</guid></item><item><title>39. Nikolai Fyodorov wanted to resurrect the dead to live among the stars</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42028697</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;59 points points by szkosma on 2024-11-02T19:39:16 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article presents a letter discussing the philosophical ideas of Nikolai Fyodorov, emphasizing his vision of a future where humanity overcomes death and achieves resurrection through technological and spiritual means. The author reflects on Fyodorov's influence on contemporary thought, highlighting themes of human responsibility towards the deceased, the potential for collective progress, and the ethical implications of scientific advancements. The letter encourages readers to consider how Fyodorov's ideas can guide modern society in addressing existential challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fyodorov's philosophy is a key driver of the plot of the trilogy of novels by Hannu Rajaniemi, starting with https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Quantum_Thief&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Has some similarity to Tipler's "omega point" hypothesis iin his 1994 book "The Physics of Immortality" [1]. I read this years ago but have recently bought it again to have another look at. It seems to be a PDF on the Internet Archive as well. It was a very wild idea.[1] https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_J._Tipler&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;For those in LA, there’s a related exhibit at the Museum of Jurassic Technology. Definitely worth checking out if you haven’t been, the whole collection is a delight.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:31:23 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42028697</guid></item><item><title>40. Ham radio enthusiasts who help keep the NYC Marathon running smoothly</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42037750</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;43 points points by wglb on 2024-11-04T02:04:18 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the use of ham radio operators during the New York Marathon to enhance communication and safety for the event. It highlights how these volunteers provide crucial support by relaying information about the race, assisting with medical emergencies, and ensuring that organizers can communicate effectively across the vast event. The piece underscores the importance of amateur radio in emergency situations and public events, showcasing the skills and dedication of the ham radio community.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Where's Nextel PTT when you need it?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Happy to see coverage of ham radio volunteers here! The Boston Marathon has a similar volunteer-led program which I've participated in since college [1]. It's such a fun event and a great way to combine technical interests with community service. I'd highly recommend it to anyone looking to join a community of like-minded technical folks. The group isn't what the "old men with radios" stereotype would suggest either.[1] https://www.arrl.org/news/amateur-radio-provides-communicati...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Quick plug for anyone who may be interested in ham but a little intimidated by the license that’s required. Contact your local ham club or group (I guarantee you there is one). Ours had a fast track to getting people licensed. It amounted to a one day cram course immediately before the technician’s exam (the oddly named entry level license) with a 90+% pass rate. The philosophy is to get people licensed and on board and interested and THEN start learning. It’s kind of a counter intuitive strategy but it certainly got me involved where I wouldn’t have been otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:31:33 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42037750</guid></item><item><title>41. NASA remains silent on why crew went to hospital after dragon splashdown</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42092385</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;77 points points by bookofjoe on 2024-11-09T03:40:57 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses NASA's lack of communication regarding an incident involving a SpaceX Crew Dragon splashdown that resulted in crew members being sent to the hospital. Despite the significance of the event, NASA has not publicly addressed the situation or provided details about what occurred during the re-entry and landing process. The lack of transparency raises concerns among space enthusiasts and experts about safety protocols and the handling of emergencies in space missions.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is exactly the kind of headline that would appear 20 minutes into a B-rate sci-fi movie.As we approach Act II, an intrepid young journalist rushes to the hospital to find out what’s really going on… But wait, who is in the black car trailing her?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some people seem to deal with long-term zero-G better than others. The cosmonaut who spent the longest continuous time in space was Valeri Polyakov, who spent 437 days in zero G in the early 1990s, came back fine, had a good career after returning, and recently died at age 80.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Could it be an initially-unnoticed chemical leak in the Crew Dragon? That could explain how it hospitalized four astronauts at once, and also why they're uncharacteristically afraid of media coverage. They were evasive in a similar way when Starliner was first having issues—they're scared of the politics, or of the lawyers.edit to add: These spacecraft all use very toxic fuels, and this one has had issues with fuel leaks before [0]. I'm not sure how or if those could affect the crew. Maybe if there was contamination on an exterior surface, they could have been exposed on landing? IIRC it is or used to be standard procedure to take air samples before opening crewed spacecraft, for this reason.edited again to add: I found it! It Apollo-Soyuz in 1975—the entire Apollo crew were poisoned by fuel when they opened the spacecraft, and were hospitalized with chemical pneumonitis [1,2].[0] https://arstechnica.com/science/2022/06/nasa-delays-cargo-dr... ("NASA and SpaceX stand down on Dragon launch to study hydrazine issue")[1] https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apollo–Soyuz#Re-entry_and_afte...[2] https://ntrs.nasa.gov/citations/19770023791 ("The Apollo-Soyuz Test Project: Medical report")- (wiki) "The only serious problem was during reentry and splashdown of the Apollo craft, during which the crew were accidentally exposed to toxic monomethylhydrazine and nitrogen tetroxide fumes, caused by unignited reaction control system (RCS) hypergolic propellants venting from the spacecraft and reentering a cabin air intake. The RCS was inadvertently left on during descent, and the toxic fumes were sucked into the spacecraft as it drew in outside air. Brand briefly lost consciousness, while Stafford retrieved emergency oxygen masks, put one on Brand, and gave one to Slayton. The three astronauts were hospitalized for two weeks in Honolulu, Hawaii.[22] Brand took responsibility for the mishap; because of high noise levels in the cabin during reentry, he believed he was unable to hear Stafford call off one item of the reentry checklist, the closure of two switches which would have automatically shut off the RCS and begun drogue parachute deployment. These procedures were manually performed later than usual, allowing the ingestion of the propellant fumes through the ventilation system.[23]"&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:31:43 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42092385</guid></item><item><title>42. A Random Walk Through Ada (2014)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091724</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;60 points points by okl on 2024-11-09T00:57:31 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The webpage discusses the long-term effects of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) since its enactment in 1990, highlighting both its successes and shortcomings. It examines how the ADA has contributed to increased accessibility and rights for individuals with disabilities, while also critiquing areas where implementation has fallen short. The article presents a nuanced perspective on the ADA's impact on various aspects of society, including employment, education, and public spaces, ultimately advocating for continued efforts to improve and enforce disability rights.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;For those interested in trying Ada out, I wrote a a Rustup-like app that installs Ada's package manager (Alire) on macOS and Linux: https://www.getada.devIt was also featured on HN (194 points | 6 months ago | 117 comments: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40132373I've gone from not having anything Ada related on my computer to installing the toolchain, initiating a project , writing, compiling, and running "Hello World" in less then 2 minutes.Ada has had something of a resurgence in the last couple years, with the latest standard (2022) officially released and for the first time in a few years, Ada has its own dev room at FOSDEM! https://fosdem.org/2025/news/2024-10-28-devrooms-announced/There's also a growing community at ada-lang.io with a thriving forum: https://forum.ada-lang.io/&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&gt; It being a one-pass compiler bugs me (there is no excuse for a modern language to require forward declarations).He refers to the need for forward declarations as "one-pass compiler".  Historically at least, Ada compilers were infamous for requiring many passes and being consequently slow.Whether it is still acceptable for a programming language to require forward declaration seems to me rather a matter of personal taste.  Sure, compilers improved and there's plenty of memory for them to use, but human programmers' capacity increased little, if any, I'd think.  I think of those forward declarations as form of double-entry bookkeeping.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I once did an engineering camp at the Air Force academy and in one of the classes we programmed Lego mindstorms with Ada - something like https://www.adacore.com/academia/projects/real-time-mindstor...I do wish we had better options for embedded! Even C++ isn't making much headway against C when it comes to programming microcontrollers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:31:53 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091724</guid></item><item><title>43. Cache Directory Tagging Specification (2004)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093541</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;19 points points by networked on 2024-11-09T09:59:29 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website provides a directory for cached items related to the Bford project, offering resources such as scripts, tools, and documentation that assist in managing and utilizing cache systems. It serves as a repository for users to access and share various cached files and info associated with Bford's initiatives. The site aims to streamline the process of finding and using cached resources effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I think this is my favorite lesser known spec, for whatever reason. I smile whenever I run across a CACHEDIR.TAG.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support in rsync seems to be lacking, unfortunately: https://github.com/RsyncProject/rsync/issues/499&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:32:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093541</guid></item><item><title>44. SQLite does not do checksums</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42094663</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;126 points points by todsacerdoti on 2024-11-09T14:41:22 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article details a vulnerability found in SQLite, which can be exploited through a bit-flipping attack. This type of attack manipulates the binary representation of data to alter its meaning or behavior when processed by the database, potentially allowing attackers to gain unauthorized access or corrupt data. The author explains how such vulnerabilities can arise, emphasizing the importance of security measures in database management and providing insights into the technical aspects of the SQLite architecture that enable these exploits.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL, one of the most popular databases for reliable data management, also does not enable this feature by default."By default, data pages are not protected by checksums, but this can optionally be enabled for a cluster. "
https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/checksums.htmlI feel it's quite unfair for the title to call out sqlite on checksums, when in reality, as the very closing line of the article states most databases don't do checksum verifications.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sqlite is the wrong layer at which to care about storage hardware failures. That would be the job of the disks themselves, the hardware or software volume manager, or filesystem.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The checksum in the WAL is to detect incomplete writes (due to crash or power failure). That data was never committed successfully. Throwing an error for this scenario would mean that sqlite is unable to recover from a crash.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:32:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42094663</guid></item><item><title>45. SQLite is not a single connection database</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095012</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;76 points points by Igor_Wiwi on 2024-11-09T15:47:29 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article addresses common misconceptions about SQLite, clarifying its capabilities and limitations. It highlights that SQLite is not just a lightweight database for small applications but is also capable of handling complex workloads and concurrent transactions effectively. It dispels myths regarding its performance and scalability, emphasizing that SQLite is suitable for a variety of applications beyond mobile and embedded systems. The piece aims to educate readers on the true nature of SQLite and its appropriate use cases, encouraging a more informed perspective on database choices.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Missing from this, but very important: you can connect to the same SQLite database file multiple times inside the same process (e.g. in different threads) but you can also connect to the same SQLite database file from multiple different processes on the same machine (with the same filesystem - NFS will lead to all kinds of nasty problems).Easy way to prove this to yourself: run two different terminals, run "sqlite3 data.db" in each one, run create table / insert / update queries in one and watch the results become visible to selects in the other.Changes only become visible to other connections after they have been committed.In default mode any writes will hold an exclusive lock and will cause any reads to be blocked waiting for that lock. In WAL mode reads can continue even while writes are taking place.Writes can only run one at a time, but can queue waiting for each other to finish - and since most writes take microseconds to run this is very rarely a problem.The most complicated thing to understand is the need to use BEGIN IMMEDIATE TRANSACTION in concurrent environments to avoid the occasional SQLITE_BUSY exception. The best explanation I've seen of this is here: https://fractaledmind.github.io/2024/04/15/sqlite-on-rails-t... - search for SQLITE_BUSY.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I just dealt with a lot of sqlite concurrency stuff recently. When I first got started, a lot of recommendations were that apps should create a connection and hold that connection its the duration. This works great but I feel like it's worth noting that this can get dangerous when you're working in a multi-threaded context.You can have one thread in the middle of stepping through the results of a SELECT prepared statement and if another thread resets the statement and runs it again, that original thread will start stepping through the results from the other thread's call.  Or if both threads begin a transaction, you'll get nested transaction errors.Things get really confusing, especially because you might not notice the problems until the app is running on a slower machine.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There are benefits to having a single writer connection (and multiple readers).One is that you can get fairer and more efficient locking. The (interruptible) file lock APIs that SQLite uses lead to a lot of sleeping and retrying that wastes time, and is not very fair.https://fractaledmind.github.io/2024/07/19/sqlite-in-ruby-ba...Another some APIs, like the backup API, work better if they can track writes, and (e.g.) backing up from the single writer connection helps there.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:32:23 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095012</guid></item><item><title>46. There aren't enough smart people in biology doing something boring</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095513</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;62 points points by abhishaike on 2024-11-09T17:13:02 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the shortage of individuals with high intelligence and critical thinking skills in various fields, highlighting the implications this has for innovation, problem-solving, and societal progress. It emphasizes the importance of fostering education, promoting creativity, and developing skills that encourage higher-level thinking to address the challenges posed by this deficit. The piece calls for a reevaluation of current educational practices and societal values to cultivate a smarter workforce capable of tackling complex global issues.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strongly disagree. Easily 99% of people in biology are doing very tedious boring things. Maybe you just don’t hear about it because it’s “boring”.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Software engineering and finance have completely sucked the air out of the STEM room.I'll be surprised if in a generation anyone in the US knows how to build anything other than JavaScript apps and swap agreements.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This post doesn't address the elephant in the room -- wages in biology seem to be supressed due to an oversupply of life sciences scientists willing to do tasks in various corporate and academic labs.Since life science wages (rewards) seem to be so low compared to other careers in relation to the density of advanced degree holders, the ambitions need to be that much bigger to make it worth it to found uncertain and risky startups. Only big ideas would be worth funding. Ecosystem tooling startups might be founded once more capital for that category trickles in.&gt;&gt;And I have no doubt that Patrick Collinson — the CEO of Stripe [...]Patrick's last name is Collison, not Collinson, as per the wikipedia link that the blog post references.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:32:33 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42095513</guid></item><item><title>47. Following up "Mother of all Htmx demos"</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091909</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;89 points points by thunderbong on 2024-11-09T01:39:07 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses a comprehensive demonstration of htmx, a JavaScript library that enables developers to build interactive web applications with less complexity. It highlights various features of htmx, including its ability to handle HTTP requests and update parts of the webpage dynamically without requiring a full page reload. The author emphasizes the benefits of using htmx for enhancing user experience and simplifying code. Additionally, the demonstration presents practical examples that showcase how htmx can be implemented in real-world applications, illustrating its effectiveness in improving web development workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is a follow up to a presentation David gave at the 2022 European DjangoCon:https://htmx.org/essays/a-real-world-react-to-htmx-port/His talk was a major milestone in the arc of htmx, showing that a real world, commercial project could move from react to htmx and see significant benefits. I can't stress how important his talk was in the overall success of htmx, and I'm glad he followed up on it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;My only counter is that for a real-time collaborative app the server should be the single source of truth about application state, which would make htmx a good choice for that type of application.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Any major websites using htmx?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:32:43 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42091909</guid></item><item><title>48. Automat: A tangible interface for virtual things</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42041129</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;23 points points by surprisetalk on 2024-11-04T13:00:47 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automat.org is a platform focused on the intersection of technology and cultural production, offering a space for collaboration and dialogue among artists, technologists, and thinkers. It aims to explore how emerging technologies can influence creative practices and societal engagement, highlighting innovative projects, research, and events that foster interdisciplinary connections. The website features articles, interviews, and resources that encourage critical discussions on the impact of technology on contemporary art and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I watched for about a minute (up to the mouse clicks and keyboard modifiers) and have no idea what is being demonstrated that I'd want in the real world. Couldn't scroll to find text explaining it to me. Neat proof-of-concept where I have no clue what is being proven. Perhaps OP (if affiliated) can elaborate?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I really like what you did here, especially the attention to detail like the transparency of the VHS tape and the R/RW hole in the floppy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fun website. Still no idea whats going on and why 3.5 is inserted like a SD card though&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:32:53 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42041129</guid></item><item><title>49. Astronauts tight-lipped about reason for hospital visit after 235 days in space</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093560</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;58 points points by mindracer on 2024-11-09T10:06:44 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA is enhancing medical support for astronauts aboard the International Space Station (ISS) by establishing a hospital on the station. This initiative aims to address healthcare needs in space, enabling better management of medical emergencies and routine health monitoring. The project signifies a significant advancement in astronaut care, reflecting the increasing importance of health and safety as space missions extend in duration and complexity. The hospital will be equipped with necessary medical technology and staffed by experts to ensure astronaut well-being during missions.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Comments moved to https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42092385.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If deep sea divers need to come back to the surface slowly so their bodies can reacclimate to standard pressure, do astronauts undergo a similar reacclimation process as it pertains to gravity?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;My rough understanding is that it's a very strange environment for the body to be in for an extended period of time, and when you come back, gravity hits you very, very hard.It seems like they all absolutely would need to have detailed tests when they come back. Whether there was another illness or emergency who knows. But the shock of sudden gravity could trigger things.I think this type of headline just gets views because people want to believe they made alien contact or something ridiculous.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:33:03 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42093560</guid></item><item><title>50. Writing Tiny Desktop Apps in C and GTK3 (2022)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42070807</link><description>
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;64 points points by aard on 2024-11-06T22:51:35 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the development of minimalistic GTK applications for Windows and Linux, highlighting strategies for creating lightweight apps that prioritize efficiency and simplicity. It provides insights into the tools and frameworks that can be used, along with practical coding examples. The author emphasizes the importance of user experience and performance, offering tips on how to achieve a clean and responsive design without unnecessary bloat. Overall, the piece serves as a guide for developers looking to build small, effective applications across both operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Top Comments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&gt; You'd better not dare write your desktop application in HTML. What has this world come to???Ok thats clear. But then ten sentences later:&gt; Of course, you aren't going to write your UI in C, only an idiot would do that. Instead, you want to write it in some kind of markup language.Now, let me think of some markup language that is universally known and has at least some pretence to be about laying out information on a screen... Thats right, html.The thing with UI frameworks in the 21st century of flying cars, AGI and rapidly approaching Singularity, is that its a stagnating mess.There should be a nice, standardized, cross-platform, easy to get started and progressively expandable way to build high quality visual apps. For some elusive reason, we cant have good things.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trivial examples of Gtk+ apps seem to be legion but to find a decent tutorial that works its way through a moderately complex and usable app seem to be scarce.  In particular I haven't found a decent example of using the GTKBuilder class and complete documentation of the XML properties seems almost nonexistent.Aside from that, instead of writing a GNOME app in C, isn't Vala or GJS the preferred language now?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nice post but the images don't load for me&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:33:13 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42070807</guid></item></channel></rss>